naa.org 2018-10-09

# Privacy Policy | News Media Alliance

Effective November 1, 2016.

News Media Alliance wants you to understand how we collect, use and disclose information from and about you.  This Privacy Policy describes our practices in connection with information collected through this website as well as any websites or mobile applications operated by the Alliance, and any services or platforms that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Services”).

**1\. Information We Collect**

We collect information you give to us when you use the Services, as well as various non-personal information about your use of the services.

**Information You Provide to Us.  ** We collect information you give us when you use the Services.  For example, when you register for events, purchase our products online, or sign up for membership, we may ask for information such as your name, title, employer, mailing address, telephone number, and e-mail address.  We may also collect payment information, such as your credit card information, to process a financial transaction you have requested.

**Public Information and Posts.  ** We collect comments or content that you post to the Services and the information about you that accompanies those posts or content, which may include a name, user name, comments, likes, status, profile information and picture.  Public Information and Posts are always public, which means they are available to everyone and may be displayed in search results on external search engines.

**Automatically Generated and Usage Information.    **Our Services collect routine information from all visitors when they use the Services, including hardware model, IP address, other unique device identifiers, operating system version, and settings of the device you use to access the Services.  In addition, when you access and interact with the Services, we and our service providers may collect certain information about those visits.  For example, the Alliance contracts with a third-party web measurement analysis firm in order to collect information about the ways visitors use the Services.  As part of this relationship, we may collect information about your access content on our Services—including articles, reports, and downloads—and respond to advertising messages.  We also may use cookies and other tracking technologies (such as browser cookies, pixels, beacons, and Adobe Flash technology including cookies) in connection with our analysis of usage.  We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by third-party service providers.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, but you can change your settings to notify you when a cookie is being set or updated, or to block cookies altogether.  Please consult the “Help” section of your browser for more information.  Users can manage the use of Flash technologies, with the Flash management tools available at Adobe’s website at <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>.  In addition, users can opt-out of certain usage information collection activities by visiting the website of our third-party web measurement analysis firm at <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#5>.  Please note that by blocking cookies and other technologies, you may not have access to certain features, content or personalization available through the Services.

**Information from Other Sources.  ** We may supplement the information we collect with information from other sources, as permitted by law, which we may combine with other information we receive from or about you.  For example, we may receive information about you from a social media site if you connect to the Services through that site.

**Other Information We Collect.  **We also may collect other information  about you, your device, or your use of the services in ways that we describe to you at the point of collection or otherwise with your consent. You may choose not to provide us with certain types of information, but doing so may affect your ability to use some of the Services.

**2\. How We Use Information**

To Provide and Manage the Products Services You Request.  This includes, for example, processing your purchases of products, enabling you to participate in features provided by the Services and in our stores.

To Better Understand Our Users and to Improve Our Services. The Services may collect information on our users’ demographics, interests and behavior and analyze that data. We do this to better understand and serve our users, and to improve our products and services.

**To Contact You.  **We may periodically contact you with offers and information about the Services and our affiliates, including to inform you about our products, events, promotions, and special offers. Where required by law, we will obtain your specific consent.  You may opt out of receiving commercial email messages from us by following the instructions contained in those email messages.

**To Deliver Targeted Advertising.  **We may use your information, including your location information, to facilitate the delivery of targeted ads, promotions, and offers to you, on behalf of ourselves and advertisers, on and off the Services.

**To Protect the Rights of the Services and Others.  **We may use your personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, its employees or agents, or other users and to comply with applicable law.

**Consent.  **We may otherwise use your information with your consent or at your direction.

**3\. How We Share Information**

**Social Media Services.** If you connect a social media account with the Services or engage with our services through a social media platform, we may share your information with that social media platform, and it may share information about you with us. We may use this information to personalize your experience on the Services and on the third-party social media platforms, or to provide you with offers or other products or Services you may request. The social media services’ use of the shared information will be governed by the social media services’ privacy policy and your social media account settings. If you do not want your information shared in this way, do not connect your social media service account with the Services.

**Affiliates.  ** We may share information with our affiliate, the American Press Institute, as appropriate.

**Service Providers.** We may share information with companies providing services on our behalf, such as delivery services, hosting vendors, advertising service providers, data analytics companies, marketing service companies, and list managers. We also may share your information, including your payment information, as appropriate to complete a transaction.  Our service providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and we do not authorize them to use or disclose personal information for their own marketing or other unrelated purposes.

**Trusted Business Partners.  ** Information that you provide to us—such as information you provide when you register or product-purchase information—may be provided to trusted third-party business partners, including exhibitors or attendees of our events.  Exhibitors represent the universe of news and publishing industry suppliers, including programmers, manufacturers, service-providers, and consultants; attendees represent a cross-section of news management and related parties, including supplier personnel.  Third parties who receive information are governed by their own privacy policies in how they process information we provide to them, and are not bound by this Privacy Policy.

**Other Parties When Required or Permitted by Law, or As Necessary to Protect Our Users and Services.  **We may use and share your personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, our employees or users, to detect, suppress or prevent fraud  or where otherwise required or permitted by law or legal process, including responding to requests from public authorities.

**Other Parties in Connection With a Corporate Transaction.**  We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event that we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets to a third party, such as in the event of a merger, acquisition, or in connection with a bankruptcy reorganization.

**Otherwise With Your Consent or At Your Direction.**  In addition to the sharing described in this Privacy Policy, we may share information about you with third parties whenever you consent to or direct such sharing.

**Aggregated Data.**  We also may provide aggregated information, and data with personal identifiers removed, to third parties to describe how our customers are using the Services.

**4\. Security**

We employ administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures to safeguard information in its possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification.  However, no system of safeguards can be 100% effective, and we cannot guarantee the complete safety of your information.

**5\. User Access and Control**

You may control your use of cookies and other technologies as described above.  If you want to stop receiving promotional materials, you can change your account setting email us at [info@newsmediaalliance.org](mailto:info@newsmediaalliance.org) or follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

**6\. Other Important Information**

**Updates to Privacy Policy.**   We may modify this Privacy Policy.  Please look at the Effective Date at the top of this Privacy Policy to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised.  Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Services.

**Location of Data.**   The Services are hosted in and managed from the United States.  If you are a user located outside the United States, you understand and consent to having any personal information processed in the United States.  United States data protection and other relevant laws may not be the same as those in your jurisdiction.  This includes the use of cookies and other tracking technologies as described above.  As a result, please read this Privacy Policy with care.

**Linked Services.  ** The Services may also be linked to sites operated by unaffiliated companies, and may carry advertisements or offer content, functionality, games, newsletters, contests or sweepstakes, or applications developed and maintained by unaffiliated companies.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of unaffiliated companies, and once you leave the Services or click an advertisement you should check the applicable privacy policy of the other service.

In addition, we are not responsible for the privacy or data security practices of third-party  organizations, such as Facebook, Tumblr, Twitter, Apple, Google, Microsoft or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider, or device manufacturer, including in connection with any information you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with the Services.

**Children’s Privacy.  **We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13 without parental consent, unless permitted by law. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law.

**7\. Contact Us**

**Questions.  ** Please contact us at [feedback@newsmediaalliance.org](mailto:feedback@newsmediaalliance.org) or (571) 366-1000 with any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy.
